Welcome back for Unit 3.
欢迎回到单元3
This unit introduces the next big idea we need for a web crawler,
这个单元会介绍 下一个对于网络爬虫的重要思想
which is structured data.
也就是结构化数据
And by the end of this unit you will have finished building a working web crawler.
在这个单元的最后你会完成创建一个网络爬虫
The closest thing we've seen so far to structured data
目前为止我们所看见离结构化数据最近的东西
is the string data type introduced in Unit 1 and used
是在第一单位介绍的字符串数据类型
in many of the procedures in Unit 2.
在第二单元被用在许多函数中
A string is a kind of structured data, and that's because
一个字符串是一种结构化数据 那是因为我们
we can break it down into its characters.
可以把它分解成单个字符
The string has a sequence of characters,
字符串有一序列的字符
and we can operate on sub sequences of the string.
并且我们可以操作字符串的子序列
What we could do with strings was somewhat limited, though,
然而 我们可以对字符串做的是有限的
because the only thing we can put in a string is a character.
因为我们可以在字符串中放的只有字符
Today, we're going to introduce the list data type,
今天 我们将介绍列表数据类型
and lists are much more powerful than strings,
列表要比字符串强大很多
so whereas for a string, all of the elements had to be characters,
对于字符串 所有的元素都必须是字符串
in a list, the elements can be anything we want.
在列表中 元素可以是我们想的任何东西
They could be characters. They could be strings.
它们可以是字符 它们可以是字符串
They could be numbers. They could also be other lists.
它们可以是数字 它们也可以是其他的列表
Let's look at an example.
让我们看一个例子
When we created a string, we just put a sequence of characters
当我们创建一个字符串时 我们只是在单引号或者双引号中
surrounded by either single or double quotes.
放了一连串的字符
Here's an example of a string,
这里是字符串的一个例子
and we could store that string in a variable by using an assignment.
然后我们可以用等于将字符串储存在一个变量中
With a list, instead of using quotes to identify the list
在列表 我们用方括号而不是引号
we use square brackets, and the elements are separated by commas.
来定义列表 列表的元素用逗号分开
And just like with a string, we can assign the list that we created
接着就像字符串那样 我们可以将我们创建的列表赋给
to a variable, so we'll store that list in the variable "p."
一个变量 所以我们会将那个列表储存在变量 p
With a string, we could use the square brackets
在字符串中 我们可以用方括号
to select elements, and when we index element 0,
来选择元素 然后当我们索引元素0时
we'll get the first element of the string, a sequence of that character,
我们会得到字符串的第一个元素 一个字符的序列
which is the character "y."
也就是字符 “y”
With lists, we can also use square brackets to access elements,
在列表中 我们也可以用方括号来访问元素
so if we do p[0],
如果我们用 p[0]
that will evaluate to the first element of p,
就会得到 p 的第一个元素
which is the string containing the single letter y.
其为包含单个字母 y 的字符串
With strings, we saw that we could use the colon inside the square brackets
在字符串中 我们看见我们可以在方括号中用分号
to select a sub string of more than 1 character.
来选择大于一个字符的字符串的子字符串
Here we're selecting from position 2 through position 4.
这里我们选择从位置 2 到位置 4
That will give us the third and fourth characters of the string,
那会给我们字符串中第三个和第四个字符
which is the sub sequence, the string "bb."
其为一个子序列 字符串 "bb"
We can do the same thing with lists.
我们可以对列表做同样的事
We can select from position 2 to position 4,
我们可以选择从位置2到位置4
but instead of returning a string, it will return a list
但是它会返回一个列表其包含
containing those elements.
那些元素 而不是字符串
It will give us a list of the third and fourth element
它会给我们一个包含变量 p 的第三个和第四个元素
of the variable p, which is the list that we have here.
的列表 也就是这个列表
The general grammar for constructing a list
建立列表的一般语法是
is to have a square bracket followed by a list
用一对方括号包含
of any number of expressions where the expressions
一个由任意数量的表达式组成的列表
are separated by commas.
表达式之间被逗号分开
We could create a list using just 2 brackets,
我们可以只用两个括号创建一个列表
a left bracket and a right bracket, and this would create a list
一个左括号和一个右括号 接着这会创建一个列表
containing 0 elements, also known as the empty list.
包含着0个元素 也就是空列表
We could create a list containing 1 element.
我们可以创建包含一个元素的列表
That would be the square brackets with 1 element between them.
就会变成一对方括号和一个元素在里面
Here we've created a list containing just 1 element,
这里我们已经创建了包含一个元素的列表
which is the number 3.
也就是数字3
Or we could create a list with many elements, as we did in the first example,
或者我们可以创建一个列表包含许多元素 就像我们在第一个例子中做的那样
where we have all of the strings separated by commas.
其中我们将所有字符串用逗号分开